别招惹你妹妹
Step away from your sister.
Karen 上楼换衣服去
Karen, go up and get changed.
Ben 你能不能别玩那个了
Ben, will you stop playing with that!
听着 最后一次 你决不能也不要再打人了
Listen, for the last time - you should never, ever, hit a person.
- 如果他们用铁锹袭击我怎么办 - 什么
- What if they're attacking you with a shovel? - What?
如果有人用铁锹袭击你的话
If someone's attacking you with a shovel,
你绝对应该回击他
you must be able to hit them.
好吧 显然 没错 我是说 那是防卫
Well, obviously, yeah. I mean, that would be self-defence,
所以很显然 在某种
so obviously, in that sort of
涉及到铁锹的情况下 你能打别人 但
shovel-related circumstance, you can hit someone but.
哈 可你说了 “决不 再不要”
Ah, but you said "Never, ever"!
Ben 你理解的很对
Ben, you know perfectly well.
大家赶紧的 可别在这个婚礼上也迟到了
Come on people! Let's not be late for another wedding! Ah.
今日的神秘物件是
And today's mystery object is.
电视机后的泥铲 Karen 你准备好了嘛？
a trowel behind the telly. Karen, are you ready?
听着 Ben 你决不能先对别人动手
Look, Ben. You must never hit someone first.
如果你是一个拳击手呢
What if you're a boxer?
- 如果你是个拳击手 你就能揍别人了 - 听着
- If you're a boxer, you should be able to hit someone. - Listen!
因为拳击手的工作就是揍人
..Because a boxer's job is to punch people.
- 但我们没有在讨论 - Karen
- But we're not talking about... - Karen!
如果有人走向你
What if somebody's walking
而且你知道他们是杀手
towards you and you know they're a murderer.
- Ben - 他们还拿着铁锹
- Ben... - And they have a shovel.
Ben 这不关拿着铁锹的杀手什么事
Ben, this isn't about murderers with shovels...
- Jake 能别发短信了吗 - 还有啊 为啥一定要我穿这种衣服
- Jake, can you stop texting? - Why have I got to to wear this stuff anyway?
- 又难看又刺痒 - 大家赶紧的
- It's horrible and itchy and... - Come on, everyone!
我们要去参加个婚礼
We're going to a wedding,
每个人都不得不这样装模作样的
and everyone has to be as uncomfortable as humanly possible.
这是规定 现在去吧 快点 把你的鞋子穿上
It's the law. Now go, come on, get your shoes on.
Karen 你需要帮忙吗
Karen, do you need some help?.
不不 我们不是说好了 要到Julie家里之后
No, no... I thought we'd agreed you were going to change into your dress
你才换上你的裙子 和另一个伴娘一样
when we got to Julie's house, like the other bridesmaid.
- 但我想试穿一下我的裙子 - 可是宝贝 那样就
- But I want to travel in my dress. - But darling, it'll get...
你不该在我大喜的日子里让我不高兴
You're not supposed to upset me on my big day.
严格说起来 Karen
Well, strictly-speaking, Karen,
今天是Julie表姐大喜的日子 不是吗
it's cousin Julie's big day, isn't it?
我真希望大家别再说这话了
I wish everybody would stop saying that.
去换回你原先穿的那套吧
Go and change into what you were wearing before.
谁第一个走过通道呢 是我还是另一个伴娘
Who comes down the aisle first, me or the other bridesmaid?
这由Julie表姐决定 所以我们就只能听候她安排了
That's up to Cousin Julie, so we'll wait and see what she wants wouldn't we?
谁第一个走过通道呢 Julie表姐还是我呢
Who comes down the aisle first, Cousin Julie or me?
当然是Julie表姐了
That would be Cousin Julie
因为她才是新娘啊
on account of the fact that she's the bride.
现在去换衣服吧 Karen
Now go and get changed, Karen.
我来接
I'll get that!
- 我们得走了 快点儿 - 嗨 老爸 你好吗
- We've got to shift, come on! - Hi, Dad. How are you?
老爸 Angela姨妈是不是要参加婚礼啊
Dad, is Auntie Angela coming to the wedding?
这个
Well...
她没回复邀请
She hasn't replied to the invitation,
而且美国离得远
and America's a long way away,
而Angela姨妈总是让人难以琢磨 所以
so you never really know with Auntie Angela, so...
老天 我希望她和老妈别再干架了
God, I hope Mum and her don't have another fight.
其实那也不能算是真正的干架 对吧
Well, it wasn't really a fight exactly, was it?
至少没用到铁锹
No shovels involved.
对 但她们对吼
No, but there was shouting,
尖叫 还对骂 骂的很厉害
screaming and swearing. A lot of swearing.
你看 所有的姐妹之间总有些小分歧
Look, all sisters have these little disagreements,
而且我想如果她来的话
and I'm sure that if she does come,
她们会非常和谐的化解的
they'll be very civilized about it.
不管怎样 她多半是来不了了
Anyway she probably won't come.
妈的 都这个点了
Bollocks, the present!
- 老天 - 你还好吧
- God! - You OK?
不好 是我爸 他彻底忘记了婚礼了
No, that was Dad. He's forgotten all about the wedding,
现在还只穿着睡衣呢
and he's still in his pyjamas.
我脑袋蹦蹦的跳着痛
I've got a thumping headache
而Karen对她的裙子小题大做的
and Karen's faffing about with her dress!
Karen 你这是干嘛去
Karen, where are you off to?
- 我要上厕所 - 好吧 需要帮你脱掉裙子什么的吗
- I need a wee. - OK. Do you need any help with your dress and stuff?
- 我都六岁了 - 行 但别插上那个门栓 因为不太灵活了
- I'm six. - OK, but don't slide the bolt across, cos it's stiff.
什么
What?
我说 你要小心别插上
I said, can you make sure you don't slide the...
门栓
..Bolt across.
好吧 呃 Karen 亲爱的 听着 你能否 呃
OK, erm..Karen, darling. Listen, can you, erm...
能帮我个忙吗
Can you do me a favour?
你能把门栓再拨回去吗
Can you just put the bolt back across again?
你明白我的意思 我知道你行的
You know, just so I know you can.
我办不到 卡住了
I can't. It's too stiff.
你应该警告我别插门栓啊
You should have warned me not to put the bolt across!
甜心 其实我真心是说了的啊 只是
I think it was mentioned actually, sweetheart. But just erm...
总之别担心 你会没事的
There's nothing to worry about, you'll be fine.
那 你既然可以把它拉到一边 那你就
Well, you slid it one way, you should...
你就能把它拉回另一边
You should be able to slide it the other.
赶紧的各位 我们出发了
Come on everyone, let's go!
Ben 别那么做 我们得多给自己
Ben, don't do that. We need to allow ourselves
留点儿时间 因为你老爸他信不过导航仪
plenty of time because Dad doesn't trust the sat nav any more.
就因为那次跑到军队靶场去了 这该死的蓝药瓶
Not since that visit to the army firing range. Bloody (junk)blue bottles!
谢谢
Cheers.
只要用力的推就好
Just give it a big push.
她出不来了 她永久的被困在那里了
She won't get out, she'll be stuck forever.
Ben 那样说根本于事无补
Ben, that is not helpful thing to say.
- Karen - 你应该提醒她别插门栓的
- Karen... - You should have told her not to put the bolt across.
可笑的是 我正是
Funnily enough, that was exactly...
你得把门打破才行
You'll have to break the door down.
你介意吗 我会处理这事的
Do you mind? I'm dealing with this.
在《警察故事》里 他们都是用那种好大好大的专用破门锤
On The Bill, they have this really really big special door-basher,
就像个金属大棒
that's like a big metal pole.
不幸的是我们没有那种金属大棒
Unfortunately we don't have a big special door-basher
专用破门锤 所以
with a long metal pole so...
万一她要是渴了 喝了厕所的水怎么办
What if she gets thirsty and drinks the toilet water?
那其实没什么的 Karen
Well, that'll be fine. Karen!
- 这是怎么了 - 我被困在厕所了
- What is going on? - I'm stuck in the toilet.
你不该让她插门栓的
You shouldn't have let her put the bolt across.
好吧 要是再有人这么说的话
Right, the next person who says that...
好吧 让我们先别慌
OK, let's try not to panic.
没有人慌啊
No-one is panicking.
- Karen慌啊 - 谢谢你 Jake 我已经意识到了
- Karen's panicking. - Thank you, Jake. Yes, I am aware of that.
如果她能把门栓合上
If she slid the bolt one way,
她就应该能再拉开的啊
she should be able to slide it back.
就是说啊 所以我刚才就
Yes I know, and that is why I have been...
好吧 让我们先冷静下
OK, let's try to stay calm.
- 我很冷静 - 这铁定会让我们误点的
- I am calm. - This is going to make us late.
我们不能迟到啊 这可是我大喜的日子
We can't be late! It's my big day!
没事儿的 Karen 淡定点儿
It's all right Karen. Stay calm.
我们可以把几只海狸从窗户扔进去 让它们咬门
We could put beavers through the window and they'd eat the door.
听着 我们能停止讨论用海狸什么的蠢建议吗
Look! Can we please stop with the stupid suggestions about beavers?
- 没必要惊慌的 - 救命啊 - 我没慌啊
- There's no point in panicking. - Help! - I am not panicking.
我们不会迟到的
We're not going to be late.
我会搞定这事的
I will deal with it. And I
而且我会冷静的 妥善的处理此事
will deal with it in a calm and measured way.
换那个门要花多少钱呢
How much will it cost to replace that door?
你瞧 我让咱们及时赶到了 不是吗
Look, I got us here on time, didn't I?
有时严峻的形势下需要采取严厉的措施
Sometimes drastic situations require drastic measures.
- 那你的肩膀还好吗 - 还好
- So, how's your shoulder? - Fine.
- 你的脚呢 - 还行
- And your foot? - Yes.
- 那你的 - 打住 我们能先别 行吗 - 你还好吧 外公
- And your... - Look, can we just... OK? - You all right, Granddad?
什么 哦 没事没事 就是在欣赏新娘
What? Oh, yeah, yeah. Just admiring the bride.
Judy看起来真是赏心悦目 不是吗
Judy looks smashing doesn't she, eh?
是Julie啊 外公
It's Julie, Granddad.
是吗 哦哦 是吧
What... Oh. Oh, yeah.
女孩们 我看起来怎么样
So, girls, how do I look?
- 你看起来很漂亮 - 哈 谢谢你 Karen
- You look beautiful. - Ah, thank you, Karen.
我看起来漂亮吗
Do I look beautiful?
凑合吧
You look OK.
你看起来美极了 Mary
You look gorgeous, Mary.
为什么结婚礼服是白色的呢
Why are wedding dresses white?
因为妈妈说白色不好 它很容易脏的
Because Mummy says it's a bad colour because it shows the dirt.
那倒是事实 我是说白色的确不耐脏 对吧
That's true, I mean it's not very practical, is it?
还有 为什么婚纱那么搞笑呢
And also, why are wedding dresses funny?
- 搞笑吗 - 是啊 因为当我在车上问爸妈
- Funny? - Yes, because when I asked my Mummy and Daddy in the car
新娘是否要穿婚纱的时候 他们回答 “是的”
would the bride be wearing white, they said, "Yes",
然后就开始咯咯的傻笑
and started giggling.
是吗
Did they?
他们还想掩饰来着 不过我看到妈妈的肩膀
And they tried to hide it but I could see Mummy's shoulders
就这样上下抖啊抖的
moving up and down like this.
这样啊 好啊
Right. Great...
好了 Ben 再提醒你一次 那是碎石 这是五彩纸屑
Right, Ben, a little reminder. Gravel. Confetti.
你上次在Sandra阿姨的婚礼上
You seemed to get confused
把这两种给弄混了 对吧
at your Auntie Sandra's wedding, didn't you?
当牧师问
When the priest says,
“是否有人反对这两人的结合”时
"Does anyone know any reason why these people
不准喊出什么奇怪的答案 可以吗
"Can't get married", no shouting out funny answers, all right?
- 你是说 比如 “她是个男人”之类的吗 - 是的
- You mean like "She's a man"? - Yes!
正是如此
Exactly like that.
你应该庆幸你Sandra阿姨的
You're lucky your Auntie
幽默感还是蛮好的
Sandra's got such a good sense of humour.
- 那是谁啊 - 是Sam 我们曾约会过几次
- Who's that? - That's Sam. We used to go out together.
你有多少个男朋友会来观礼呢
How many of your boyfriends are here?
不是很多 就几个 几个而已
Not many. A few, a few.
那么 那个秃头的呢
What about... What about the bald one?
- 哦 Colin啊 - 我妈喜欢他 - 是吗 Colin不在 他不会来的
- Oh, Colin. - My mum liked him. - Did she? No Colin, Colin's not here.
那么那个和女皇是朋友的呢
What about that one that was friends with the Queen?
你说什么
Sorry?
和女皇是朋友 他和女皇是
Friends with the Queen He's friends with...
朋友 你知道的啊 他和女皇是好朋友啊
of the Queen, you know, he's friends with the Queen.
他是女皇的客人啊
He's a guest of her majesty.
是啊 是啊 不 他 他也不会来
Right. Right. No, he's... He's not here.
他住在白金汉宫吗
Is he at Buckingham Palace?
不 他不住在白金汉宫
No, he's not at Buckingham Palace.
170.5
我妈妈不喜欢他
My mummy didn't like him
看起来 你爸妈会讨论
So, your mummy and daddy were
我选男友的品味了 是吗
discussing my taste in boyfriends, were they?
- 是的 - 好吧
- Yes. - Right.
谁是Ulrika呢
Who's Ulrika?
我也不知道我遇到
I don't know what I would
北极熊袭击时会怎么做呢 Ben 大概会装死吧
do if I was attacked by a polar bear, Ben. Playing death probably.
现在赶紧坐下吧 就坐你妈旁边
Now, come on, sit there. Space by your Mother.
- 不行 不可以 - 行 当然可以
- No, there isn't. - Yes, there is.
- 这里不行 瞧啊 - 那不是空位嘛
- No there isn't, look. - There's a space.
你旁边那里不是明显有个空位嘛
There's quite obviously a space next to you.
- 为什么要挨着我 为什么要挨着我啊 - 去吧 Ben 挨着Jake坐
- Why next to me? Why next to me? - Come on, Ben, by Jake.
这场景让我回想起了自己结婚那天时的情景
This is brings back so many memories of my wedding day.
拥挤的教堂 每个人都盛装出席
A crowded church, everyone in their finery.
还有Jane 噢 Jane 她是那么的漂亮
And Jane. Oh, Jane. So beautiful.
她美的令人惊叹
Breathtaking she was.
爸
Dad...
妈妈的名字是Joan啊
Mum's name was Joan.
我知道 但她有个
I know, but she had this
很靓的朋友叫做Jane 是个绝色尤物
gorgeous friend called Jane. Real stunner.
我真是不敢相信你 你刚刚
I can't believe that you... that you just...
并不能因为你要结婚了 就不再欣赏美女了吧
Just because you're getting married doesn't mean you got stopping admiring beautiful women.
可是就这样 在这圣坛前吗
But that's just... At the altar?
得了吧 男人都是这样的
Oh, come on. It's just what men are like...
那么 你要发誓爱他到永远
So, you promise to love him forever and ever,
但你怎么知道这是真的呢
but how do you know that's true?
我就是知道 我爱Derek 简单明了
I just know. I love Derek. That's all there is.
那你就不爱其他你那些
So you didn't love any of
男朋友了吗 比如那个秃头的
those other boyfriends, like the bald one,
还有那个是女皇的朋友的
and the one that was friends with the Queen?
我想我曾经也是爱过他们的
Well. I suppose at the time, you think you love them...
- 但是最后你发现那几次你都错了 - 是的
- Then it turns out that you were wrong all those times. - Yes.
但是这次你确定了
But you're right this time.
是的
Yes.
真是大好结局啊
And that's happy and good.
是大好结局
That is happy and good.
为什么耶稣的脸上是悲伤的表情
Why has Jesus got that sad expression on his face?
这个嘛 他被
Well, he's being...
钉在十字架上 那令他很痛苦
crucified and it's making him feel sad.
他手都被钉子钉住了 他一定会 “啊啊”大叫
He's got nails in his hands. He should be going, "Aargh".
- Ben 安静 - 他一定会的
- Ben, sssh! - Well, he should.
- 多愁善感的老耶稣 - Ben 别那样
- Soppy old Jesus. - Ben! Please!
- 这一点都不现实 - 你能不能就
- It's not realistic. - Would you just...
嗨 快看 那是Angela 她到底还是来了 真是太好了
Hey look, it's Angela! She's made it, isn't that brilliant?
哦 是啊 还真是好呢
Oh, yeah. That's... That's brilliant.
嗨 嗨 Pete 嗨 老爸 Sue
Hi! Hi, Pete! Hiya, Dad, Sue.
嗨 Jake. 嗨 Ben
Hi, Jake. Hi, Ben.
- 我好难过啊 - Ben
- I'm so sad. - Ben!
- 他没什么变化呢 对吧 - 你能来真是太好了
- He hasn't changed, does he? - It's fantastic you could make it.
恐怕只是个短暂停留
It's just a whistle-stop tour, I'm afraid.
我的老板离不开我啊
My boss can't spare me for long.
当然离不开 是啊
Course not, no.
到这儿来
Come here.
- 你认识Derek多久了 - 十个月
- How long have you known Derek? - Ten months.
- 那可不怎么长啊 - 哦 看哪 好可爱的楼梯
- That's not a very long time. - Oh, look! What a lovely staircase.
我爸妈不在一起生活了
My mummy and daddy don't live together any more.
妈妈说在他们结婚的那天
Mummy said that on their wedding day,
她曾以为他是这个星球上最棒的男人
she thought he was the most wonderful man on the planet.
现在她就一直哭
Now she just cries all the time.
这就开始了 甜心 准备好了吗
Here we go, sweetheart. All set?
Julie眼里含着泪呢
Julie's got tears in her eyes.
那是啊 激动人心的一天
Well. It's an emotional day.
那是谁
Who's that?
- 不知道 - 我们在这桌
- No idea. - This is our table.
他们把Ben和Karen分到儿童桌了
They've put Ben and Karen on a children's table.
- 好极了 - 真的吗
- Result! - Is it?
Ben坐在儿童桌呢
Ben is on a children's table.
和其他小孩一起
With other children.
你能不能别当直升机家长啊
You can't be a helicopter parent.
你总是盘旋在他身边
You just hover around him all the time.
你都不给他什么空间 他会没事的
You don't give him any space. He'll be fine!
就算有的话 也只是个垂直起降飞机的家长
More of a sort of jump-jet parent, if anything.
我喜欢快速切入去解决问题
I like to just get in there quickly and sort stuff out.
老天 是你啊 Howard
My God, it's you, Howard!
你好啊 Vicar
Oh, hello Vicar!
又来了 这个找存在感的
Here it comes, the attention-seeking missile.
- 听着 Sue 今 - 今天是Julie大喜的日子 我知道
- Look, Sue. This... - This is Julie's big day, yes I know.
我想要说的是
All I was going to say is...
我必须要再三克制 是的 我懂
That I must stay in control. Yes, I know that.
而且你也不用担心
And you needn't worry,
因为我向自己保证了
because I have made a promise to myself,
不管Angela怎么激怒我
and no matter how provoking Angela gets,
我都会无视并忍下来的 好吗
I am simply going to choose to rise above it. OK?
- 好吧 - 好 好 解决了
- OK. - OK. OK, sorted.
那个 她貌似控制得不错 不是吗
Well, she, eh...seems to be on top of it, doesn't she?
是啊
Yeah.
- 她们要走个对面了 - 我去解决
- They're walking towards each other. - I'm on it.
- 嗨 Angela姨妈 你好 - 嗨 Jakey
- Hi, Auntie Angela, hello. - Hi, Jakey.
漂亮的桌牌
Nice table display.
是啊 是的 真是 真是不错的桌牌
Yes, yes, it's a... it's a very nice table display.
我喜欢那种漂亮的老式桌牌 你呢
I like a good old table display, don't you?
如果你要坐在儿童桌的话
If you're going to sit on the children's table,
你必须做到不打架 不喝
you got to do no fighting, no drinking
成人饮料 不骂人 你明白吗
grown-up drinks and no swearing. Do you understand?
因为我们决定信任你
Cos we're gonna trust you.
- 信任我吗 - 是的
- Trust me? - Yeah.
你是要信任我吗
You're going to trust me?
是的 还有你不能和这个小女孩掰腕子
Yes. Only, you mustn't arm-wrestle this little girl
- 因为她看起来才三岁 - 是四岁
- cos she only looks about three. - Four.
她才四岁
She's four.
- 你还好吧 Pete - 呃
- You all right, Pete? - Erm...
- 是啊 Frank 是的 - 新娘倒是躲起来了
- Yeah, Frank, yeah. - The bride's certainly putting it away.
搞不好是大赛神经紧张的后遗症呢 Frank
Probably a case of big-match nerves, Frank.
我能再问你一个关于圣经的问题吗
Can I ask you another question about the Bible?
呃 当然 你问吧 Ben
Erm. Well, of course you can, Ben.
希律王下令要杀了幼儿耶稣 是吧
King Herod sent out an order to kill the baby Jesus, right?
是的 没错
Right, yes, he did. Yep.
那为什么幼儿耶稣没反击干掉他呢
Well, why didn't Baby Jesus zap him?
是啊 我 我认为在理论上他的确能
Well, yes, I... I suppose in theory he could have...
干掉他 他…
zapped him, he...
因为希律王对于耶稣来说是微不足道的
Because Herod, was a tiny little speck of nothing to Jesus,
耶稣用一只河马就能压扁了他 或者…
cos Jesus could have squashed him with a hippopotamus or...
但是耶稣总是逆来顺受的
But Jesus was meek and mild.
是啊 说的没错 Karen
Well, yes, that's true, Karen.
况且 他还知道当希律王下地狱后
And besides, he knew that when King Herod got to Hell,
上帝会让他在火上炙烤 直到他的眼球都爆掉
that God would roast him until his eyeballs exploded.
还有啊 为什么上帝只给我们
And why has God only given
留下十五万亿年好生存
us fifteen thousand billion years left to live,
- 就熄灭了太阳呢 - 呃…
- before the sun dies? - Erm...
- Sue 嗨 - 嗨
- Sue, hi! - Oh, hi!
最近还好吧
So, how's things?
还不错 你最近怎么样啊
Ooh, things are good. How're things with you?
挺好
Good, yeah.
- 你还住在Keely大街吗 - 是 是啊 我们还在那儿
- Are you still in Keely Road? - Yeah, yeah, we are.
你还 还住在…
Are you... Are you still in..?
老地方 是啊
The same place, yeah.
- 你带着孩子们过来的吗 - 是啊
- Have you got your kids with you? - Yeah.
- 什么 三个都来了吗 - 是啊 - Karen应该六岁了吧
- What, all three? - Yes. - Karen must be, what six?
六岁了 没错 你们呢 你们家的孩子呢
Six, yes. Yes, how about you? Have you got your...offspring?
对啊 他也来了 Pete和你一起过来的吗
Oh, yeah, he's around somewhere. Have you got Pete with you?
- 我们想见见他 - 嗯 这个就是Pete - 嗨
- We'd love to meet him. - Oh, um... This is Pete. - Hi.
Pete 这位是…
Pete this is...
真不错 不是吗
Lovely, isn't it, this?
他们安排的这个…
What they've done with this...
这位是我的父亲 这位是…
And this is my dad and this is...
这是你的座位 老爸 这里
where you're sitting Dad, here.
你们坐在哪里呢
Where are you sitting?
呃 就在这个桌子 和你们一起
Erm, on this table, with you.
太好了 真是太好了 因为这种状况下你总会担心
Great! That's great, because you're always worried
被安排和谁在坐在了一起
about who's gonna be on the table with you at things like this.
我们可以放心了 因为我们和
We're gonna be OK because we've got...
Paula和Steve坐在一起
Paula and steve!
欢迎你们 Paula和Steve Steve和Paula
Welcome, Paula and Steve! Steve and Paula...
那你们怎么认识Sue的呢
So where do you know Sue from?
你想告诉他吗 还是我来呢
Do you want to tell him or shall I?
还是你来说吧 Paula
You tell him, Paula.
Angela怎么不和我们在一桌呢
Is Angela not on our table then?
我们能调换一下吗
Can't we do something about that?
我觉得这样打乱座位安排不太合理呢 Frank
It wouldn't be fair to disrupt the seating plan, Frank.
人家可是下了大工夫的啊
A lot of work's gone into that.
当耶稣长大了一些后
When Jesus was a bit older,
他仍然被罗马人通缉着
and he was still being searched by the Romans,
- 为什么他不变形 - 变形吗
- why couldn't he shape shift... - Shape shift?
变成罗马人 然后当其他罗马人都睡着后
..Into a Roman, and then when all the other Romans were asleep,
他就能杀了他们 这样他们也就不会再通缉他了
he could kill them so they would stop searching for him.
我很怀疑他会这么做呢
Yes, well I doubt he would do that.
他并不是恐龙战队之类的人物
He wasn't a Power Ranger or anything like that.
我可以再问你个问题吗
Can I ask you another one?
这是最后一个了吗
Is this the last question?
- 不是 - 好你说 - 当耶稣…
- No. - Oh, OK. -When Jesus...
那么谁想来点儿酒呢 来点儿吗
So, who'd like some wine? Wine?
这可真搞笑 一定是搞错了
Oh, this is daft, there must have been a mix-up.
我来把这俩个调换一下
I'll just swap this one for it.
这样调换座位可不太好吧 这…
I don't think it's fair to disrupt the seating plan, it's...
我想他们不会介意的 不管怎样
Oh, I'm sure they won't mind, anyway,
- 我们能坐在一起就好嘛 对吧 - 是啊 真不赖
- it'll be nicer if we're all together, won't it? - Yes. Be lovely.
耶稣会原谅那些坐着大火箭升到
Would Jesus forgive somebody if they flew up to heaven
天堂的人吗
in a big rocket
而且如果他刚到天堂
and as soon as he goes to heaven
他就一拳揍到耶稣的脸上 还痛揍了耶稣一顿
he punches Jesus in the face, and he beats Jesus up.
耶稣会说 “我原谅你” 还是
Would Jesus say, "Oh, I forgive you", or would he...
还是会噗呲一下就反击回去
or would he fight back, "Pittsh",
把那人打飞出天堂呢
and knock that man out of heaven?
我不认为能升入
I just can't see a situation
天堂的人
where somebody would get into heaven,
会 会揍耶稣
and... and...punch Jesus.
还有 当我…
And also, when I was...
圣经所要传达的意思是我们应该宽于待人
The message in the Bible is that we should forgive
更重要的是 耶稣是为了我们而死
and it was important that Jesus died for us.
他为了救我们大家而死的
He died to save us all.
所以人类还是有些自私的 对吧
That's a bit selfish of humankind, isn't it?
那为什么他不想点儿别的法子 比如写点儿什么警告
Well, couldn't he find another way, like writing to tell them
他们乖一点儿 否则
to be a bit better otherwise
就会有坏事发生了 又或者…
something bad's going to happen, or like...
Oh 上帝啊 呃 我真的得走了
Oh, goodness! Erm, I really must be going...
当耶稣被钉上十字架时…
When Jesus was being crucified...
事实上 我刚意识到那有些人
Actually, I've just realised there's a few people
我必须过去打个招呼
I must go and speak to.
让上帝砸下一颗陨石
..Ask God to send a meteorite
摧毁罗马人的部队
and destroy the troops of the Romans...
那就是上帝所选择的方式了
Well, it was the way that God chose.
他决定牺牲自己唯一的儿子
He wanted to sacrifice his only son.
他以此彰显此事的重要性
He wanted to show how important it was.
他选择了这个世上对他来说最重要的东西
He chose the most precious thing in the world to him,
而这个世上对他来说最重要的东西就是耶稣
and the most precious thing in the world to him was Jesus.
那他为什么想让他死啊
And then why did he kill him?
那你有孩子吗
So, have you got kids?
没 没有 你要知道 我的生活大概容不下孩子了
No. No, my lifestyle's never really left any room for it, y'know?
我热衷于环游世界
I love my globetrotting too much.
- 这样啊 - 是啊 我效仿不了Sue
- Right. - No, I couldn't do what Sue does.
耶稣说我们应该宽恕他人
Jesus says that you should forgive everybody.
是 说的没错 抱歉 你是谁
Yes, that's right. Sorry you are?
她叫Mary 我的助理伴娘
This is Mary, my assistant bridesmaid.
好了 我要走了
OK. I'll be off.
那如果有人偷了耶稣的手机
So what would Jesus do if
他还会原谅他们吗
someone stole his mobile, would he forgive them?
对 他会原谅他们 他会的 你是正确的 Ben
Yes, he'd forgive them. yes，he would. you're right, well done, Ben.
我现在必须要走了
Now I really must be going.
- 等等 最后一个问题 - 那好 - 如果耶稣被一只北极熊袭击
- Wait! One last question. - Ok. - What would Jesus do.
- 他会怎么做呢 - 他会灭了它
- if he was attacked by a polar bear? - He would zap him.
- 他才不会灭了它 - 这不可能啊
- He wouldn't zap him! - That can't be true.
- 北极熊可是要灭绝了啊 - 我不是存心想让你伤心…
- Because polar bears are extinct. - I didn't mean to upset you...
- 你该知道的啊 - 他们才不是呢 他们很危险
- You should know that! - They're not, they're endangered.
不对 因为北极熊很少
No because there's not much of polar bears,
但我们却有很多
but there's lots of us
这个世界上有差不多五万亿的人
there's about five trillion people in the whole world
却只有大概五只北极熊
and there's about five polar bears in the whole world,
- 那我们就应该照顾他们 - 好吧 所以我…
- and so we have to look after them. - All right so I...
如果你和一群北极熊遭遇了 那最后的几只
If you went up to a group of polar bears, the last ones,
你说 “北极熊 我站在你们那边”
and you said, "Polar bears, I am on your team.
“我们一起猎杀人类吧”
"Lets hunt down the humans",
他们会扑向你 杀了你的
they would pounce on you and kill you.
- 好了 孩子们 - 有可能 可我也不是非要那么做 不是吗
- Kids, please. - Probably but I'm never gonna do that, am I?!
- 你真是蠢极了 - 没必要这么说吧 Ben
- You're being so stupid. - There's no need for that, Ben.
不 我才没有呢 Benny
No, I am not, Benny!
- 笨蛋 - 别吵 别吵 冷静些 孩子们
- Dummy! - No shouting, no shouting. Calm down please, children!
是啊 我效仿不了Sue
No, I couldn't do what Sue does.
我是说 我真的很敬佩她
I mean I really take my hat off to her,
照顾Pete和孩子们 日复一日的 我是说
looking after Pete and the kids, day in, day out, I mean,
她总是甘愿成为滑稽的配角 我可做不来
always having to play second banana as it were. I couldn't do that.
是啊 我十分艳羡我的妹妹
No, I've got huge admiration for my little sister.
她就像是个可爱的超级辣妈 而我呢 对吧
She's like this lovely supermum and what am I, eh?
其实
Well...
每人有每人的活法 是吧
Each to their own, eh?
- 完全正确 - 老爸
- Absolutely... - Dad.
如果每个人都是绝对的相同 那生活一定很无趣
..Life'd be pretty dull if everybody led absolutely identical...
- 老爸 - 我正在说着话呢 Jake
- Dad. - I'm in the middle of saying something, Jake.
是 但是 Ben和Karen两个要咬起来了
Yes, but, Ben and Karen are trying to bite each other.
该死的
Oh, shit.
没事儿的 Vicar 我来处理此事
It's OK, Vicar, I'll deal with it.
给我回来
Come back here!
- 我对它们过敏 - 你不对豌豆过敏
- I'm allergic to them! - You are not allergic to peas.
没人对豌豆过敏
No-one's allergic to peas,
这世上就没人对豌豆过敏
no-one in the world is allergic to peas.
你怎么知道 你又没有问人们
How do you know, because you... you haven't asked the people,
即使你问了 我也知道你在撒谎
even if you did I know you'd be lying
因为你没法问印度人 你没法问日本人
because you can't speak Indian, you can't speak Japanese...
你没法问澳大利亚人 还有其他人
you can't speak Australian or any of that.
豌豆专营管理局曾做过调查的
There was a survey by the Pea Marketing Board.
听着 快吃了这些豌豆 拜托啦
Look, just eat the peas, please.
就就就就 不不不…
No, no, no... but, but, but, but...
Ben Ben 你不可以把沙丁鱼浸到巧克力喷泉里去
Ben! Ben, you can't dip sardines in the chocolate fountain.
可以的 你能 看啊
Yes, you can! Look!
瞧瞧 他能啊
See! He can!
老爸 穿过那两扇门就是了
Dad! It's through the double doors.
老爸的记忆力看起来越发不好了
Dad's memory seems quite a lot worse.
这是个逐步退化的疾病 所以…
Well, it is a degenerative illness, so...
他迟早都是要
Sooner or later he's going to have
- 搬离那幢房子的 - 我心里有数
- to move out of that house. - I'm well aware of that.
那你开始着手寻找
So have you started looking into sheltered
- 老年公寓之类的了吗 - 必要时 我们会的
- accommodation and stuff? - We will, when the time comes.
没必要去否认这件事
There's no point going into denial about it.
也许你可以从美国回来 来照顾他
Perhaps you'd like to come back from America and look after him.
好像有次你就是这么说的
Like you once said you would.
是啊 这就对了 我刚才还好奇呢 到底多久才…
Oh, yes, here we go. I was wondering how long it would...
听着 我只是不想和你吵
Look, I just don't want to have an argument with you.
让我们别破坏了这一天 那样太没面子了
Let's not spoil the day. It would be a shame.
是啊 我们总是能得体优雅的文明处理事情
Yes. We've made a pretty decent fist of keeping things civilized,
不是吗 除去故意把座位分开的小问题不说
haven't we? Apart from the seating arrangement hiccup.
这事儿和我毫无关系
That was nothing to do with me.
拜托 莫非你真以为
Oh, come on, do you really think...
你爱信不信 我就是不想和你吵
You can believe what you like, I am just not going to fight with you.
好了 谁想喝一杯 那儿有个现卖吧台
Right, who wants a drink? It's a cash bar now.
另一个伴娘家里养了三只宠物 我们能养一个吗
The other bridesmaid's got three pets. Can we get one?
- 不行 - 没门
- No. - No.
你可真是个漂亮的伴娘啊 Karen
You made a lovely bridesmaid, Karen.
你做过伴娘吗
Have you ever been a bridesmaid?
做过啊 做过几次
Yeah. A couple of times.
- 但没做过新娘 - 没有
- But never a bride. - No.
- 为什么啊 - 我 我没有你老妈那么幸运
- Why? - Well, I... I wasn't as lucky as your mummy.
我不想对第一个求婚的男人点头说“我愿意”
I didn't want to say "Yes" To the first man who asked me.
我们最好打道回府吧
We'd best be making tracks.
是 是啊 你说的没错
Yeah. Yeah, you're right.
你还得考虑到晚上A3高速的道路情况
You got to allow for the A3 this time of night.
您好
Hello?
- 真高兴见到你们 Paula和Steve - 再见 - 慢走啊
- Lovely to see you, Paula and Steve. - See you! - Yeah, drive safely.
你能把Karen带上汽车吗 还有 嗯…
Could you get Karen to the car, and, erm...
把Ben也顺便叫一下吗
could you round up Ben on the way?
- 因为我得去和Julie表姐道个别 - 拜 - 拜
- Cos I'm going to say goodbye to Cousin Julie. - Bye. - Bye.
- 我得溜出去抽根儿烟 - 好
- I'm just popping out for my nicotine fix. - Oh, OK.
抱歉 我们要回去了
Sorry... We're going to head off now,
我只想过来和你说一句
so I just thought I'd come
这婚宴真是太棒了
and say thank you for a really lovely do,
还有 谢谢你让Karen当伴娘 她…
and thanks for making Karen a bridesmaid, she's...
- 她全身心的投入其中了 - 是啊 她就是这样的孩子
- She certainly threw herself into it. - Yes, she's that kind of kid.
她把我以前的男友进行严刑逼供呢
She gave me the old third degree about my boyfriends.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
她看起来对他们其中的大多数了如指掌啊
Yeah, she seemed to know quite a lot about most of them.
你晓得的 那个年龄段的孩子大都如此
Well, you know what girls that age are like.
是啊 我晓得 还问我“谁是Ulrika啊”
Oh, yes, I do. Full of questions, like, "Who's Ulrika?"
- 那个 我们得走了啊 - 真高兴Angela也能来
- Well, we better be making tracks. - Nice that Angela could make it.
- 是啊 可不嘛 - 对啊 我和她好好闲话了一番 - 是吗
- Yes, really... - Yes, she and I had a good old chinwag. - Did you?
- 大部分是关于你家孩子们 - 真的吗
- About your kids, mostly. - Really?
- 你知道的 当她打开话匣子时那样子 - 是啊
- You know what she's like （when she's going）. - Oh, Yeah.
- 你不想知道她都说了些什么吗 - 不想
- Don't you want to know what she said? - No.
她说 Jake很有可能是个同性恋
She said Jake is probably gay,
因为他对花样的装饰物特着迷
because he's obsessed with floral displays,
她说 Karen是个被宠坏 而且爱控制人的孩子
she thinks Karen is spoilt and manipulative,
她还说 Ben一副早期精神病患者的样子
and she thinks that Ben is a trainee psychotic.
- 是嘛 - 还有啊 Pete弱得像个娘们
- Right. - And Pete is "Weaker than a nun's piss".
这个说法是不是很有趣啊 弱的像个娘们
Isn't that a funny expression? "Weaker than a nun's piss".
好了 还是要谢谢你的款待了
OK, well, thanks again for everything.
不 是我该谢谢你啊
No, thank you.
很高兴认识你…
Very nice to meet you...
- 都搞定了吗 - 是啊 - 那 稍等我一下
- All set? - Yeah. - I... Won't be a second.
真抱歉麻烦你帮我家的孩子们调停
I'm so sorry you had to separate our children.
没什么 没事儿
Oh, no problem, no problem.
他们还真是蛮活泼的一对 不是吗
They really are a lively pair, aren't they?
- 活泼吗 还真是呢 - 是的
- Lively, they are. - Yes.
- 是啊 - 是啊 让我在脑子里不停的想着
- Yeah. - Yes, I'm still pondering the question,
“耶稣会不会也怕遇到氪星陨石呢”
"Is Jesus vulnerable to kryptonite?"
不管怎么说 还是要十分感谢你帮了大忙 真是谢谢了
Anyway, thank you very much for a lovely service. Thanks again.
- 好了吗 - 好了 - 拜拜
- Ready? - Yeah. - Bye. Bye.
- 妈妈 你了解监狱吗 - 监狱吗 知道啊
- Mum, do you know jail? - Yes, I know jail.
那是不是非常调皮的人才会被送进去呢
Well, is it just like a big naughty step?
是啊 正如你所说的一样 没错
Yeah, that's exactly what it is. Yeah.
- 但是只有高墙和大狗 - 是啊
- But only with walls and dogs. - Yeah.
回到床上去 不 Ben 不行
Back up to bed. No, Ben, no!
- 让我过去 - 不行 Ben - 为什么我不能看足球
- Let me past. - No Ben! - Why can't I watch the football?
因为已经很晚了 好了 赶紧上去
Because it is late. C'mon. Up you go.
但我一整天的表现都很好啊
But I've been on my best behaviour all day long.
先前就告诫过你 “不打架
You were specifically told "No fighting,
不骂人 不喝酒”
no swearing and no drinking alcohol",
我可是当场抓到你
and I caught you bashing
往墙上打那个孩子的头部 还大吼着
that kid's head on the floor and shouting,
“你该死的别碰我的啤酒” 得了吧
"Don't touch my bloody beer". Come on.
- 那是因为他不尊重我啊 - 少来了 睡觉去
- But he was disrespecting me. - Come on. Back to bed.
如果你进了监狱的话 他们还会让你晚上回家吗
If you went to jail would they let you come home at night?
我可不会进监狱的啊 你怎么会这么想呢
I'm not going to go to jail! What made you think of that?
如果你在街上遇到某人 又揍了他的话
If you went up to somebody in the street and punched them,
- 你会进监狱的吧 - 这个嘛 也有可能
- would you go to jail? - Well...erm, probably.
如果你遇到某人 又踢了他一脚 你会进监狱吗
If you went up and kicked somebody would you go to jail?
踢了某人吗
Kicked somebody?
正中臀部
Right up the bottom.
这样啊 好了
Right, OK.
首先 我不会因为踢了Angela阿姨一脚就进监狱的 因为……
A I'm not going to go to jail for kicking Auntie Angela because...
那是她自找的 其次…
she asked for it. And ……
谁会那么傻求着别人踢自己屁股啊
Who'd ask for somebody to kick them right up the bottom?
其次 我们也不会告诉其他人的 对吗
And B we're not going to tell anybody, are we?
因为我们不想让爸爸和外公心烦
Because it would just upset Daddy and Granddad,
所以他们没必要知道 对吧
so they don't need to know, do they, hmm?
现在 我们来聊点儿别的吧
Now, let's talk about something else.
好啊 那我们聊聊养个宠物吧
All right. Let's talk about getting a pet.
教子有方
第二季第1集 婚礼闹剧
翻译
甜甜圈
校对
蒙洛奇
后期
点点
《警察故事》是自1984年10月一直播放到2010年8月的 长达26季的英国最长寿警务剧集 也是有史以来英国最长寿的剧集
白金汉宫是英国君主位于伦敦的王宫 因18世纪初为白金汉公爵建造的宅邸而得名
直升机家长（父母）或怪兽家长 指不管孩子是否需要 都会像直升飞机一样盘旋孩子周围时刻等待召唤的父母
希律王因救过凯撒大帝一命受封王位 于公元前40年-公元4年统治现巴基斯坦北部的加利利和犹太地区 以残暴而闻名 马太福音2:1曾记载希律王想杀害幼儿耶稣
《恐龙战队》是美国Saban公司购自日本超级战队系列的版权，从恐龙战队兽连者开始改编的长篇电视系列剧
氪星是超人的故乡 当超人接触氪星陨石时就会特别虚弱 与常人无异 甚至更弱一些